

Art Director, Creative Lead

Address: Chicago, IL (willing to relocate.) Portfolio: RobertBuber.com Email: robertbuber@gmail.com. Phone: 1-313-424-3146

Summary:

A conceptual mind with endless curiosity, Robert Buber has spent 9 years developing & executing compelling creative projects across a wide range of premium brands.

He brings marketing strategy to life with narrative-driven visuals. His skill across media channels elevates his teams and the brands they touch.

By pairing beautiful service with beautiful concepts, he's consistently client-facing: producing innovative award-winning ideas.

Experience:

November 2021 - Present. Bader-Rutter (Chicago, IL.)

Senior Art Director.

- Leads all aspects of marketing campaigns with creative teams & production partners, giving feedback & mentorship.
 - Collaborate with writers & strategy to craft innovative campaigns across video, print, & digital platforms.
 - Craft mood boards & storyboards that articulate ideas to inspire photographers, designers, & directors.
 - Oversees production & post-production for motion design, photography, & video projects.
 - Align multiple products to wide array of brand identity guidelines & design systems.

Clients: Corteva Agriscience, Pioneer Seeds, Zoetis Animal Health, McCain Foods.

March 2021 - November 2021. Fluent360 / Team DDB (Chicago, IL.)

Art Director.

- Generate campaign platforms for Kohl's & Army tailored to reflect & respect their multicultural customers' diversity.
- Organize & execute solutions for campaigns during pandemic (remote photo shoots, illustrators, archival footage.)
 - Generate images & oversee motion graphics for social media campaigns across U.S. Army's social accounts.
 - Direct production vendors on the concepts, trends, branding, and editing for BET branded content.
 - Develop creative pitches to articulate ideas to clients & create alignment between agency partners.
 Clients: U.S. Army, Jim Beam, AARP, Kohl's.

June 2020 - March 2021. FCB, Huge, & Verb Energy (Chicago, IL.)

Freelance Art Director.

- Develop look and feel for Bud Light and Budweiser's retail summer campaigns across a wide range of branded touch points.
- Work with founders to establish visual design language and create social campaign concepts for the start-up, Verb-Energy.
 - Oversee production vendors on the creation of assets for Super Bowl activation and Topps trading card partnership.
 - Partner with creative team to design digital products, website, icons, and interactive mail pieces for Juvederm.
 - Proactively communicate project status to partners while producing large volumes of work.
 Clients: Bud Light, Budweiser, Michelob Ultra, Alprolix, Juvederm, Verb Energy, Henry Ford Health Care System.

December 2017 - June 2020. Lafayette American (Detroit, MI.)

Art Director.

- Oversee vendors of all disciplines to deliver multi-media content such as videos, posters, books, apps, and websites.
 - Bring meticulous craft to pro-bono clients like Holocaust Memorial Center & Museum of Contemporary Art.
 - Generate disruptive ideas & present them for new business pitches, product launches, and design systems.
 - Use craftsmanship and presentation expertise to help grow the agency from 3 to 30 people.
 - Work with production and project management to shape creative pipeline processes.
 Clients: Jeep, RAM, BorgWarner, McClure's, Museum of Contemporary Art, Holocaust Memorial Center, City of Detroit.

January 2015 - November 2017. GTB / WPP Ford (Dearborn, MI.)

Designer.

- Work with Creative Directors to design high-quality presentation materials (key frames, mock-ups, storyboards.)
- Develop, layout, print, and bind brand books for Lincoln, brochures for F-150, and print ads for car campaigns.
- $\ Create \ and \ organize \ digital \ archive \ of \ Ford \ trucks, Ford \ magazine, and \ vintage \ ads \ for \ anniversary \ micro-site.$
 - Chosen to work on experimental design lab for innovative problem solving on a cross-functional team.
 - Craft user interface of Ford.com with user experience team, adhering to brand standards.
 Clients: Ford Cars, Ford Trucks, Lincoln Motor Co., WPP, Detroit Bikes, Purina, Johnson Controls.

Education:

Bachelor's in Fine Arts (BFA) Major in Illustration. Minors in Advertising & Entertainment Arts.

September 2011 - May 2015. The College for Creative Studies (Detroit, ML)

Skills:

Adobe Creative Suite (incl.: Photoshop, InDesign, Illustrator, Aftereffects, Premiere), Davinci Resolve, CaptureOne, Procreate, Keynote, Sketch, Figma, MidJourney, Cinema 4D, Blender, video direction, script writing, photo direction, photo editing, retouching, print layouts, motion graphics, graphic design, user interface, brand design, typography, persuasive public speaking, presentation skills, concept pitches, treatments, coaching third-party vendors, creative leadership, mentoring creatives, building on current designs and campaigns, working within budget constraints, ability to multitask, strong attention to detail.

Awards:

ROBERTBUBER@GMAIL.COM

HELLO CONCEPT + DESIGN CREW

Let's team up.

PHONE 313-424-3146

My interest in film & TV freaks my normal colleagues out. I gotta work with people who get it for their own sake.

One day, I'm watching Wes Anderson talk about his favorite French Films. The next, I talk my way into a subscription to ADG's Perspective magazine. That night (almost any night), I'm taking online tutorials from Hollywood's most celebrated concept designers. Anytime I get a block, I think about one of the legendary talks Syd Mead gave at CCS.

Whether my stories are hidden in my notes app or on Instagram for all to see, what I've seen on the screen informs it all. I don't think there's a better position for me to drive my talent or grow my skills as a creative obsessed with using emotion to connect with consumers.

I've worked for massive brands, museums, & small family businesses. For me, the size is always the same. That of a human eye. I often create print ads that feel more like posters, video ads that feel more like movie trailers, social content that feels scripted - where every layout feels like a part of something much bigger & makes the people I advertise to want to be apart of it.

I think my talents & interests would push all the work of the Warner Bros. Discovery studios at a time when filmed content has to be both expertly crafted & masterfully marketed across media.

Thanks, B.

RobertBuber.com